<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Languages on riceset</title><link>https://riceset.com/tags/languages/</link><description>Recent content in Languages on riceset</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2023 riceset</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riceset.com/tags/languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering Mandarin with Anki</title><link>https://riceset.com/articles/studying-mandarin-chinese-with-anki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riceset.com/articles/studying-mandarin-chinese-with-anki/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://riceset.com/images/mvvm.png"/>
&lt;p>Mandarin Chinese (普通话) has always fascinated me and learning it has been a long-standing aspiration of mine. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce you to several tools I use alongside Anki to create visually appealing flashcards for Mandarin Chinese.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="anki">Anki&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anki is an open-source flashcard program that uses spaced repetition, a learning technique that increases intervals of time between reviews of previously learned material.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="pretiffy">Pretiffy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anki&amp;rsquo;s note types consist of two HTML files (one for the front and one for the back of the card) along with a CSS file. To enhance the appearance and modernize our cards, we can utilize a template named &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/pranavdeshai/anki-prettify">prettify&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naturally, we have the freedom to tailor templates to suit our individual preferences, such as opting for centered text or incorporating additional buttons. I have done exactly that, and you can access my customized template on my GitHub repository, named &lt;a href="https://github.com/riceset/NeoMnemo">NeoMnemo&lt;/a> (access it from the &lt;code>mandarin&lt;/code> branch!)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="pinyin">Pinyin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After experimenting with numerous plugins for adding pinyin to Chinese characters, the one I ultimately chose was &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/417709332">Pinyin on top of Hanzi&lt;/a>. This plugin generates pinyin readings and places them within HTML ruby tags, resulting in a visually stunning result.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="audio">Audio&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I currently use Google Translate&amp;rsquo;s voice into &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1436550454">AwesomeTTS&lt;/a> for generating audio files for my sentences.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>